Prakash Kumar

Lead Solution Advisor, Risk and Financial Advisory

Personal Info

Email

prakashthakur9302@gmail.com

Phone

+91-7737247503

Skills

Financial Reporting

Regulatory Reporting

IFRS

MS Office

Oracle

OneSource Accounts Production

Team management

Stakeholders management

Chartered accountant (first attempt) with 7 plus years of experience in the field of Financial, Regulatory & MIS reporting and Risk advisory along with experience in directing and improving operations through effective analytical & reporting skills. Talented leader with analytical approach to business planning and day-to-day problem-solving.

Work History

2022-01

Lead Solution Advisor

- present

Deloitte & Touche Assurance and Enterprise Risk Services India Private Limited, Gurgaon

- 1. Identifying risks associated with critical business process and suggesting the controls to mitigate the same
- 2. Evaluating the operating effectiveness of banking operational internal controls in terms of design and performance
- 3. Matching the Major compliance requirements to the internal controls and Line of Business to create a risk mitigating framework
- 4. Communicating with stakeholders indulged in the process to finalize the report for issues identified in the process and their corrective actions

2018-07 - 2022-01

Manager, Global Reporting

Genpact India Private Limited, Jaipur

- 1. Preparation & Presentation of Financial statements in compliance with Australian GAAP & IFRS for several Public & Private owned entities and trusts
- 2. Preparation of regulatory returns for the Australian banking company to regulators such as APRA and ABS & presented returns at Scrutiny Reviews Meetings
- 3. Financial reporting compliance in relation to Revenue recognition, Segment reporting, Contingent Liabilities, Depreciation & Impairment of Fixed assets, Consolidation and several other items under Australian accounting standards/ IFRS
- 4. Led the project to transform the manual process to automation for Financial statements preparation
- 5. Performing monthly GL close review and reporting to check the AFSL compliance and explaining the reasons for major movement using different reports in Oracle and liaisoning with different stakeholders
- 6. Helping the management with forecast reports of Revenue and Expenses
- 7. Leading a team of 12 persons to achieve the team goals along with managing the several stakeholders including LECs, CS, Audit team, Onshore team etc.
- 8. Preparing the workings for various schedules and disclosures of Financial statements
- 9. Preparation & finalization of Financial statements of a foreign bank operational in India

2018-01 - 2018-07

Deputy Manager (Finance & Accounts)

AU Small Finance Bank Limited, Jaipur

- 1. Preparation of quarterly and annual Financial statements for the bank
- 2. Preparation of Financial statements in compliance with Segment reporting standard and guidelines
- 3. Accounting for Fixed Assets module in Oracle
- 4. Preparing the workings for various schedules and disclosures of Financial statements
- 5. Preparing MIS reports on areas like Advertisement, Legal & Professional fees, Fixed Assets, Bank Guarantee and Bank Borrowings to help management decisions
- 6. Reporting to RBI in the form of DSB return for Contingencies of business

7. Implementing the internal controls with respect to Procurement to Pay (P2P) process

2015-05 - 2018-01

Assistant System Analyst

Tata Consultancy Services Limited, Gurgaon

- 1. Accounting for Fixed Assets module in Oracle
- 2. Preparing MIS reports on areas like Advertisement, Legal & Professional fees, Fixed Assets, to help management decisions
- 3. Implementing the internal controls with respect to Procurement to Pay (P2P) process
- 4. Calculation of allowable Input Tax credit on capital goods
- 5. Liaising with third parties to implement the software as per business needs
- 6. Trained in SAP FICO module

2012-04 - 2015-03

Audit Assistant

N. Bhandari & Co., Jaipur

- 1. Handled various aspect during the statutory bank audits like fixed assets, contingent liabilities, Cash retention limit & NPA verification (PCFC credit, housing loans etc.) to identify the deficiencies in the Internal control of the branch
- 2. Drafting of Long Form Audit Report (LFAR) & Tax Audit Report
- 3. Drafting of Financial Statements & compliance with revised Schedule VI
- 4. Computation of taxable income & filing of Income tax returns and TDS returns
- 5. Drafting of form 15CA, 15CB, 29B, 10CCB (for claiming under 80IC)
- 6. Verification of various export incentives like FMS & FPS incentives & export made against EPCG license for correct recognition of income
- 7. Identification of deficiencies in the Internal control & the remedial actions to increase the efficiency and to bring down the production/purchases cost
- 8. Compliance with CARO requirements & drafting its report
- 9. Filing of forms like 20B, 23AC, 23ACA, 66, 8/CHG-1, 17/CHG-4, 23B, 1A/INC-1, MGT-14, DIR-3
- 10. Preparation of CMA data, particulars of associate concerns & Project Report for loan sanction

Education

2010-06 - 2015-04	Finance & Accounting, Chartered Accountancy The institute of chartered accountants of India, Jaipur
2013-07 - 2015-06	Finance & Accounting, M.Com University of Rajasthan, Jaipur
2010-07 - 2013-06	Accounting, B.Com University Commerce College, Jaipur

Awards

2021-06	Ace Award
2020-12	Ace Award
2019-12	Silver Award
2019-06	Silver Award